This is a test of the - I'm going to do a
quick Puzzle Storm on lichess.
Okay.
Take the Rook; take the Rook.
Check, pick up the Rook.
Fork; pick up the Queen.
Hmm.
Trade off the Rook and get the
Pawn promoted; checkmate.
Doot-doot-doo; tricky.
Hmm.
I don't see what this one is.
So, just pick up
the Knight? Yes.
The other Knight was
hanging, if the King retreated.
Okay, mate in two.
Um... pick up the Rook, thank you.
Other one of these Queen forks.
Um... my Queen's under
attack; his Queen's under attack;
but I get the Knight! So, we'll trade.
Okay, free Rook, thank you.
What kind of puzzle is that?
Uh, push the King away
from the Rook; then it's free.
Uh, mate in one.
Doot-doot-doo; I can take the pawn,
make - the Rook falls,
and take the Rook. Sweet.
Uh, check, cover the guard
square, and mate. Cool.
The e7 square was critical there.
Uh...
I think this is just a free Bishop
because the Knight is pinned?
Nope! I don't know what that
one was. I will look at that one later.
Hmm. I take the Knight,
and the Rook falls? Yes.
Okay, this is just a
mate down the back rank.
Um... pick up the Queen.
Pick up the Bishop for free.
Doot-doot-doo; check.
Now, if I take the Rook,
he gets the other Rook.
So what do I do here?
I just take THIS Rook, and
then I'm up a piece. Okay
The - remove the guard with
check, and I pick up the Queen.
Hmm.
Like, I trade off the Queens;
and then I take the Bishop.
Nope! I'm in check. Okay.
I take the Bishop? It's free?
And THEN I exchange Queens? Cool.
Uh... we move the piece out of the
way, and take the Bishop with mate.
Um... King gets mated.
See, the Rook hangs. I go here, check; and
then check; and then the Rook. Thank you.
Doot-doot-doo... okay, remove the
guard from the Queen. Thank you.
Check and free Queen.
Hmm. Kill the Bishop, and
then the Pawn promotes.
Ooo! Ooo!
Nice.
La-la-la - trapped Queen.
Uh... I have to kick the Pawn out of
the way, and then this Pawn promotes.
Mmmm... this one's not so easy.
Take the Rook, and
then the Queen. Okay.
Now, to take the Knight
first; and then the Rook falls.
Oops.
Let's look at the
mistakes I made.
Okay. So, the Queen's
under attack, is the first thing.
So, I think this is just a free
Bishop. I'm going to take the Bishop.
That was it. That is it!
Let's go back here.
Okay, this one I thought I actually
got, and I just ran out of time.
You take the Knight,
which attacks the Queen;
and then you fork the
Queen and the King;
and he moves the King; and then
you can bring your Rook out of attack;
and that's it! Okay!
This concludes the test of
the Facebook Live feature.