Hey! We're going to take a
look that a game I just played,
where I made a mouseslip and I
blundered my queen;
and yet, I ended up
checkmating my opponent.
So it starts out as a
nice Queen's Gambit.
This is a blitz game: we
started with five minutes each
and we get a three minute
increment for each move.
[We] play this very natural opening
he plays the Albin Counter Gambit,
which is technically a bit
dubious, but very very playable
in a blitz setting.
The best move here is
for White to take the Pawn;
I did not take the Pawn,
because I was afraid of the
tactical complications that would ensue.
Instead I played the very quiet move
e3, and then we just play chess.
So he checks me; I block with
the Bishop; he takes; I take.
I liked the exchange because it
gives me a free developing move.
He does not take the Pawn;
instead he plays ... d6.
I develop my Bishop,
and he trades the Pawn.
He checks me. Again, free
development for me: I'll take it.
And at this point, he
brings out his Bishops.
And now he's going for the attack,
even though it's not really justified.
He's trying to pile
up on my Knight here.
He's got it pinned
against the Queen,
and he also has a pin against
the King; but I just castle,
and I'm gonna bring
a Rook to the center;
and his Queen's going to
be in some trouble,
pinned against the King.
And so, I like my position here.
He takes I take back.
And now he makes a big
mistake. He had to castle.
He had to get out of
the center with his King.
What he's done now is, he's allowed
me the chance of exploiting this
tactic where I go after his
King, and his Queen's in the way;
but, but, first to
prepare it I do Bf3,
and that puts an
attack on the b-pawn.
So I'm threatening to pin
his Queen; I'm threatening his
b-pawn; the only move which
protects both is to castle long.
Uh, this is not the best move.
So now I've got some extra space on the
queen side because my pawns are advanced;
I've got the Bishop already
trained on the Queenside;
my Knight and my Queen
can easily get there; I can
push the a-pawn; this is all
playing out very well for me.
But before I do that I moved the Rook to
e1. Why? Because when I moved the Rook
to e1, his Queen is under attack, and
there's only one way to save it: and
that's to move the Queen back.
And this is improving the
position of my Rook, and
"de-improving" the position of
his Queen. So that's what I did.
Then I bring out the Queen, and
I'm piling up on this pawn here,
threatening mate.
He's forced to weaken his - I say
"Kingside." It's not really the
Kingside; it's the side where his King is,
which is the Queenside.
So he's weakening the pawns in front of his
King. He pushes: he could push either the
b-pawn or the c-pawn.
He chooses the b-pawn. The
c-pawn would have been better,
because if you push the b-pawn,
now we've got these light-squared -
Queen's going to come
in on the light squares,
this way; and the
only way he can
protect the light squares is with his
Knight. But the Knight can't go here
because of the pawn, and
it's just not looking good at all.
So I go here. He does ... a5.
Worse and worse.
Now his pawns are very far
advanced, and he just comes in.
Can't stop it, and he goes Nb8.
At this point I felt like
I was really doing well.
I don't see an
immediate checkmate,
But this Queenside
attack is so strong.
The Queen's gonna infiltrate;
the King's going
to have to go here;
I going to bring out the Rooks;
I'm going to firebomb his
pawns; they're all going to blow up;
he's going to have an open
King; his Rook is nowhere;
his Queen is almost nowhere.
It's just really looking bad for him.
So I went to make this move,
and maybe my trackpad was
miscalibrated; maybe I was so excited;
whatever reason; instead of making
this move I ended up accidentally making...
THIS move;
which is probably the
WORST move in the position.
Oh no. As soon as I saw this
move on the board I said to myself:
No, that is not the move I meant to play
and I press the little button that says
Dear opponent: please
let me take back my move.
Takebacks are
not well thought of.
It can be abused: you make a move; you look
at the position; you don't like it; you say
No, no, no, I'm going to do this other
move instead please let me take back
and then you end up with
a game that never ends.
But this case it was obvious
that I meant to do Qb7.
It's the only move
that makes any sense
that could possibly have
mouse-slipped to this,
and my opponent said No.
I don't fault my opponent for this. I would
have done the same thing in his situation.
We're playing a blitz game.
This is a rated
game, and in blitz,
mistakes are part of the game.
You're going to make mistakes.
So he very properly
declines the takeback,
and (given that he declines
the takeback) he has to move.
There's only one
move he legally has.
He has to deal with this check.
The only way to deal with
the check is to take the Queen.
Now he's up a Queen.
So I've gone from the
computer saying +11.3,
because of Qb7+,
to -9.4. I've lost twenty
points of material.
Two Queens.
I've gone from being effectively a
Queen up, to being a Queen down.
And so I'm here. In this
move the only rational move -
In this POSITION the only
rational move is to resign.
Your down a Queen.
He - Black's going to
get his pieces in order.
He's going to finish - the - he's going
to have to develop his Queen somehow.
Uh, there's no prayer of a draw.
Certainly no way to win.
But I'm not thinking rationally.
I've just blundered my queen,
due to a mouseslip;
I've asked for takeback;
I've been refused;
I'm not thinking okay
let's - let's accept
the loss, and resign, and
move on, and play a new game.
I said no, I'm
gonna keep playing.
I'm going to play a few moves and then
maybe get a check or two;
and THEN I'll resign.
So what do I do? I play c5.
If I'm going to get a check with my
pieces that are all the way back here,
then I need to get these
pawns out of the way.
So I sacrifice a pawn. He
takes; I take back -
I DON'T take back.
I bring in the Knight.
If you want this pawn, sir,
go ahead and take it:
and that'll give me the open
file against your King.
He correctly ignores my
suggestion to take with the pawn,
and he takes with
the Rook instead.
I go here. I get the half-open
file, and I'm like all right:
somehow I'm going to get this c-pawn
out of the way.
I don't know HOW I'm going to do it, yet.
But I'm going to do it. That's what I'm
going to do. I'm going to get your King.
Somehow, sir.
He develops his Knight;
reinforces this pawn;
and he's doing good, here.
a3. What's the idea of
a3? I want to push b4!
If I push b4 right away, he
just takes with the a-pawn.
... g5. What? He is quite properly
ignoring my attack on the Queenside,
which is doomed to failure,
and he says what am I gonna
do? I need to develop my Queen,
and my Rook, so I'm gonna
push these pawns in front of them:
and then not only am I developing
my Queen, and my Rook,
I'm also attacking your King.
When you're up a Queen, what do
you do you? You try to end the game.
Okay. I push b4.
He takes. I take.
He pushes ... g4.
Kingside attack! You're not the
only one that can attack, Matt.
Now my Bishop's under attack, and I have to
be very careful what I do here,
because when I'm -
when you're down,
you need to keep your
pieces on the board.
If you let your pieces
be traded off the board,
then any hope you may
have evaporates in smoke.
That is to say the trade
offer is a powerful weapon,
in the hands of the person
who is ahead in material.
So, I retreat,
and he brings out
his Knight further.
He's going to go here; he's
going to attack my Bishop;
he's going to soften up the g-pawn;
he's going to just take the pawn.
He's got all kinds of
good stuff going on here.
I don't want my pawn to
be taken, so I'm like all right,
this pawn's going to die
but he's going to give his all.
He's going to
take out this pawn,
which is supporting this pawn, which is
covering the King, so I'm going to take it.
And I'm thinking he's going to take back
here. He doesn't do that. He takes with the
Knight instead.
This is perfectly fine.
Perfectly fine move.
It does mean though, that are no pawns
covering his King anymore.
He might have to deal with the
fact that, after I move my Knight,
his Knight is completely pinned against
the King, and it cannot move at all.
So that's what I do. I'm
like all right, I'm gonna go
pile up on this pawn
that you pushed,
and I'm gonna realize this pin
I'm pinning against your King.
He says, all right, I'm
going to protect my pawn;
and by the way I'm going
to attack your Knight;
and I'm going to get my Queen developed;
and maybe I'll slide a Rook behind it;
and I'm coming for you, Matt.
So, I play this Bishop move, because
I don't want my Knight to be destroyed.
Remember what I said:
if you're down material
you want to keep what
pieces you have on the board,
and hope, and
pray, for a miracle.
He brings his Knight over here.
The Bishop isn't there anymore, but
the pawn is. So he's threatening my King,
and i'm really worried
about this Knight fork.
You can't play the
Knight fork right away.
It LOOKS like you
can, because I've got
one,
two attackers on that square;
and he's got
the Rook defending it, and
the other Knight defending it;
but remember this Knight is not
REALLY defending, because of this pin.
So if he were to move the Knight fork
work right away, then I would just take.
It would be a free Knight.
But still, it's a concern. So I
move - I move my Rook here.
This stops the Knight fork for good
and all, because you're only attacking
one Rook; and I can
just move the Rook.
And also it brings in the idea of maybe -
maybe I double up the Rooks on the
c-file; or maybe I bring the Rook
over here, and add another attacker
to the b-pawn - to the g-pawn:
I'm activating my Rooks.
He plays ... f6. he's like all right, you
need to make a decision about what you're
doing with this
Knight. Right now.
If you're going to take the
pawn, this is your last chance.
Well I CAN'T take the
pawn. So I'm like, all right,
I can't - I don't want to
go here. I can't go here.
I can't go here.
Well, I guess I could, but
then I'd be trading off my Knight.
I - I could go here.
I could actually go here.
No, then he takes with the
Rook; then I take the Rook;
and then he takes
with the Queen.
Okay. So really the only sensible
square for my Knight to go was here.
It's not really attacking the King;
it's just kind of cozying up to him;
but it does attack the
Rook. So, alright, I'll go -
I'll go here, I get a
tempo on the Rook.
And here he says - I dunno if he
missed that I was attacking his Rook,
or he was like you know I'm willing
to sacrifice the Rook to get this move.
He pushes the h-pawn; and he's gonna bring
in the h-pawn; and the g-pawn; he's got the
Knight; he's got the Queen; he's got
the Rook. He's going after my King
with almost everything he's got.
Now I'm going to take that Rook!
Yes, sir! Now I'm only down a Rook;
and, by the way, this
check would pick up the Queen - if this
Knight wasn't here. Because this Knight.
Is pinned. So I'm - in the back
of my mind I got this g3 threat;
force the Knight to
move; win the Queen!
He plays ... h4.
He's like, all right, you push
the g3, and I'll trade it off.
And that's what I did. He takes.
Now, I have to think here:
because if I take with the h-pawn,
then this h1-square is extremely
weak. The Queen moves over here:
no more fork;
threatening mate on h1;
I have no way - good -
good way to defend it.
So no. We're going to take
with f-pawn instead. That way,
when he moves the Queen
over here, I can defend laterally;
(I can't defend with the other
Rook, because the Knight will take it;)
and then the
Knight has to retreat;
and I get the check on the
King. I don't win the Queen,
but, hey, at least my attack
has some excuse of merit.
Like, well, okay I lost a Queen, but I
got a check on you before I lost. Okay.
And he makes a huge mistake. This
throws away his win. This is now a draw.
Why? I mean, he's
threatening mate, right?
And this attack isn't real,
'cause the Knight covers it;
and I can't take the Knight
cause of the mate threat:
it just checks, and he mates me on the
back ranks with his Queen and his Rook.
Uh, the reason this loses -
or, it doesn't lose - the reason
this throws away the win -
what should he have done?
He should have gone here.
This is a much better move.
What's the difference between
this square and this square?
So, I think he was trying
to move the Queen away
trom the threat of attack,
and he was worried about me
putting my Knight back there,
and getting this check between
the Queen and the Rook -
between the - between
the Queen and the King.
But if he moves here, then I don't
have this move right away. I have to
take a move, and
support it somehow,
and it's very difficult to find
time with the attack on the King;
but with the move he played,
I can just make this
move right away;
and that is checking the King,
and now the King is in trouble.
If he tries to come forward,
then I have the check
here, and I win the Queen.
(Incidentally that
protects the Rook as well.)
So he has to go back.
And if he goes back here -
I don't know what happens. What
happens if he goes back there?
Then it's mate in
three. I get the check,
he has to go here,
and then he gets mated;
or he has to go here, and then
he gets mated the other way.
And why can't he just take the Bishop
with the Knight? Because it's pinned.
Anyway, so he can't go straight back. He
has to go back to one of the dark squares.
He goes back here.
And now I see that I have the
draw and I'm like wow! I can't believe
I got away with a
draw in this game!
So I move here,
check. He goes there,
and I'm toying with the idea of
okay I'll go here and check him,
and then he can go
either here, or here:
whichever way he
goes I check him again;
and he has to go
back, whichever way;
and then I check him on a7 again,
and we just shuffle back and forth;
until we get the
three move repetition.
But then I thought: eh,
I'm gonna throw a little fear of
God into him. He must be rattled:
he's just thrown away the
win; he's got a draw. I'm gonna
scare him a little. I'm
gonna make this check, here.
And he can take it with
the Knight: that's fine.
The Knight doesn't interfere
with my perpetual plan.
And also now, when I do
the move to a7, there's a
double-check instead of a check.
And it's not actually any better,
but it adds that level of fear -
that psychological
dimension to it.
'Cause remember you're not playing against
a computer! You're playing against another
human being; and human beings are psycho-
logical creatures; and they have fear.
So, I make this check.
He is forced to take:
that is the only legal move;
then I play the Na7+. Here he can
go left, or he can go right; it doesn't
matter; and he goes left.
A check: two legal moves here.
If he goes back to Kc8, he's walking
into that discovered check; actually,
it's a double check;
and he has to calculate okay,
what if Knight goes here, or if Knight goes
here? Is there any kind of fork
situation that I have to worry about?
There isn't, but he decides to play
it safe, and he goes in the corner;
which gives me checkmate.
So I win.
Crazy game. That is the story
of how I mouseslipped a Queen,
and ended up checkmating.
Okay, thanks for watching!