We'll play a little more.
Level three! I have
increased my level by 50%!
Uh-oh! We're tangling against a level
four! We're punching above our weight!
What are we gonna do?
I start with a Melmetal;
he starts with a Dragonite.
Oh, good: Electric is
good against Flying.
Superpower move.
I probably should have held onto this
move a little, because now it's obvious
that it's a very fast move, and
he's probably going to NOT shield.
Yeah, yeah. Um;
so I'm just gonna
farm some energy here,
and then I'll switch
over to Garchomp.
Ehh... let's not shield yet.
Let's see what he's
got. Outrage? Okay.
So yeah that
resources outrage here.
This is actually sort
of done my my doing a
and vs trade.
Now he will definitely shoe.
Because he knows I switched.
All he didn't you.
Know.
Oh dear.
Me too okay.
He hasn't shielded at all yet.
That's odd.
She just not shielding
cause
he's definitely issue here and
yeah okay.
And I'm going to show here.
Cause I want
to.
Want to save enough of that
energy to do another charge me.
The couldn't get enough.
Yeah
yeah
seriously.
Gonna die anyway.
Let's hope that he
doesn't shield this time.
Does.
That's.
God
okay
but.
Get not that.
Let's go back and
do.
This.
Definitely gonna to
here.
Come with the sealed
that church from of here
and I think I have enough.
HP left to
pull it off.
How does shields and your debt.
Now we got one
pokemon left he said
really.
Can do to steel.
I do the steel I think
I can get the still
gegen.
The steelers to steal.
Then I ended up a ferry
or psychic puts any cause.
Nothing really ugh
why did I do the steal idiot.
Why.
Prior using your charge me.
That's such a waste of
damage.
Okay this is a bad
matchup peace movement.
Yeah.
I lose.
Earthquake
nope
that's not very effective.
That's the only
have one children.
Yeah and I wouldn't it.
Alright not very effective
wins against super effective.
And this is why you don't use your
charge move when the other guy.
Was debt.
Said that church move.
For the expo.
Although to be fair I
was about to do with
them with going to.
Completely unearned
victory there.
Against
the higher though.
It'll get over one.
Are there.
The email notification.
Not very effective
we're going to sit on that.
Of
still cast for
what.
Yeah I think the.
I think this is a case
where we could just like.
Sit
and when that
I want to punish the sky.
I like the superpower is going to be
super effective against the show I get
so if he doesn't yield
than the fighting type
is going to be super
effective as normal.
And if he does show that it's
just going to use all of the shields.
So he was once you have left.
And.
Dark I think I want to
switch to ferry here.
Like various getting a start.
Oh he's a show
not.
I dunno he's gotten.
Okay.
One.
Back to this guy
getting there and.
No he's my the shoe.
This is third pokemon
he hasn't shown up yet.
Why are using layer
on a master league.
Six thirty
cp
am offended.
Alright
used on the shields
you get one free it.
Super effective.
Pokemon wasn't super
a little amount of density.
Six could.
I'm.
Doing pretty good
so far in the spent.
He was going to be.
Pokey tuned his level to
he spent at least by battles.
This is not as fierce battle.
To get.
Pier.
Okay and switch.
To use with shoe.
You have the switch advantage
I'm gonna do at age because.
I'm going to assume
that he's going to shoot.
He does not you
okay that works too.
Secretary okay.
We used to the dragon tech news because
dragging a super effective against vegan.
So weird that executor is dragon
and like chars art is not.
Does block could.
Twice.
I think all the shields are going to get
used to get dragged vs dragon he's going to
see Atlanta
these going to show
them to share with
going gonna run out of shields and they've
already against the fifth arrangement was
going to.
Kill the other.
And I'm totally fine with it.
Yeah
and he does
of the one that gets me.
Book.
Yeah.
And now it's my turn and
he's going to be destroyed
okay.
No good suit as
their pokemon is.
I do like the choice of executor like that
is a good pokemon go into master the with
that like shows.
Moxie.
Let's see.
Okay so we
to
switch back to normal.
Get that electric versus
water type of vintage.
I.
The smell metal does not know a electric
to charge me they've got playing and steel.
Like I've.
Thought about that quite a
lot then I thought yeah okay.
We could have the.
Like mela does no.
Electric
charge me but I
liked the fighting in
the sealed combination.
And he
doesn't let spoken
to die just quits.
Hello.
That was a time of darkness.
The.
Yeah.
Okay I meant.
Literally when.
I when the lesko.
That happen before the I
decided to
just show me a bucks.
Okay
because I could
do the battle please.
Alright how are we
doing here one two three.
And.
To.
Retreat for three.
Three three
get another one
to get that sweet rare candy
forget to more than we get that.
Big boost to start as.
But we've already got the pokemon
catch a pokemon reward in the bag.
So there's no pressure.
Are we battling today.
Area sixty eight.
Sixty eight or the
born in sixty eight.
I have a theory chip
the to.
Everyone who plays
pokemon go's an adult.
Like I've never seen a
kid play pokemon go.
It's not quite you have seen kids play
pokemon go but only in the company of their
parents.
Did you see what he did.
I am definitely miss you.
And.
I'm going to assume.
That now that I've shown.
My fighting move
he's going to not she'll.
The catch them his
pants down by using steel.
This is a calculated gamble.
Does he does he
showed he does okay.
So maybe that and he's just
going to see on the matter what.
How does shields now.
So
shields he doesn't have a steel
move okay that's interesting.
I could have not children.
These are steel
steel.
It's still super
effective against do.
Not steal is not very
effective against to.
Okay then I'm an
idiot I'm using the
more expensive move.
There's less effective.
Yeah we don't do a good pokemon
go to your Chevy do trash but
go.
Switch.
Yeah we do.
So you can switch is a
good chance to switch your.
To executor or right
writing vs during
I dunno like this is not alone then
executive this is regularly sector.
So it's not your typical.
In fact.
Doesn't matter how to.
Was a lot of cpu
that are not going to
the Harriet's and how we got the
ground person's electric.
How to put them on
about of shields.
Can you get when you hit.
Not affected.
I could do this all day.
How did he get to level three.
With these.
Will see people
came on in Nashville.
I guess you don't have to win
to be able to you just have to.
About.
Said it
is it
okay.
Good for him for playing.
All the way through.
But yeah you gotta love
up your book about it
actually.
Like as high as you can go.
For okay last battle to.
Lasko.
The stream.
Where loose.
Then at all on the line here.
Donald on a
level three.
He's got the verizon shirt
that music paid money.
Cause a serious player.
Pink
use the fighting to move
here it's not very effective
but.
The shields
and.
His shoe they.
Need is
that it's funny too.
Okay now he
knows it's funny too.
So now you will not shield.
I'm not going to she.
Said unless you.
You to can't do
anything against the.
Still to yes he's not
very effective to.
Loser.
Okay.
Had to get there fast
enough.
So I strike was that did a lot of
damage for not very effective.
So he's going to think it's fighting and
let it through he does not think of twenty
three
okay so I'm a switched
this one.
He's got the best
buddy ribbon on.
You've got a
here.
You get the best buddy ribbon on
make them your buddy and he gets a.
Oh and it's a shadow muted
do.
I'm gonna
say this
is correct okay.
Yeah this mutation is
not going to hell at me.
The only
benefit years that
I've got the shield that
to advantage
of that once you
have using them.
As switched the ferry.
Okay we got very vs drink.
I'm not going shoot.
I'm not concealed
chat not going do.
During the club not very effective
that was why is not to shoot.
Just.
Nom nom nom all that period
goodness of your dragonite.
What
the chant
what
I look okay.
I'm not home with very
Venus on your a chat.
Knocking shell now either chip.
This guy's got nothing against
Lucas.
Not very effective.
Yeah I'm gonna use
my church move here.
Then I'm just gonna
fast move your
dragonite to death.
I got
to book him I lived in they're
both super effective against right.
So that.
Yeah.
No
can shoot.
When the scheme of the shoot.
Very effective.
Do do do too.
Okay damage it.
It's just rubbing it in.
Gay mr pro gamer best
buddies shadow mewtwo.
How do you like them apples.
I.
Five for five
sweet
victory.
Just.
Claim my rewards here.
What do I get I
get some star dust.
And I get.
Semester stone.
Nine tails.
It's going to Bury.
Maybe the.
Planet very was the wrong choice
give them regardless
of the circle.
Does he.
Does he stay in the ball to.
Does he stay in know he
comes out of wasted by
that very.
Well.
I have any
vegetables now.
Accident through.
Excellent through.
Does he stand there.
He does.
I get.
Kind of nine tails
any good.
Guthrie to start a
nice.
Yeah that's right.
Good cool
and.
Because of the.
Perfect score I get some.
Rare candy and I get bonus start
as and I get regular rewards to oh.
Yeah this was a product position
that something.
Maybe I should play.
Pokemon go badly
leave more often.