I had only Pawns; and my opponent
made a Queen; and I did not:
but I won!
Okay.
So the game itself starts
out - that's a nice little French.
We played the Exchange.
It's very even; open.
I like these kinda
positions, from either side.
I fianchetto my Queen-side
Bishop so that I can try to get
some kind of attack on the
King-side, reinforce my d-pawn;
press - put some pressure
on this square so that
it becomes very
uncomfortable for him to occupy.
Doot-de-doo, he decides
to take this square instead.
Okay, I'm undermining the
d4-pawn, and I've got this
nice connected set of pawns here.
Doot-de-doo - he lashes
out on the kingside,
which makes this square
much more open for me,
and yet it does tend
to cramp my King;
so I put the Knight here. I'm hoping to
get the e4 square for my Pawn. I get it.
He trades off here, he's trying
to isolate my queenside pawns.
We trade Queens. Okay,
so there's not much hope of a
mating attack anymore,
with the Queens off the board,
and we're going to contest the
file. This move was a little bit weak.
What does the computer want? The computer
suggests going to f6 instead. Fine,
but the idea here is that it
solidifies the pawn on e4.
This pawn is now a
protected passed pawn,
which gives me, I think, an
advantage in the endgame,
whereas White's extra pawn is not passed.
Okay, we trade Rooks. He says
"I'm going to contest the d-file again."
All right, we'll trade Rooks again! So now
we're down to an endgame with only pieces -
no Rooks or Queens - and I make
this move which is absolutely terrible
because it allows White to go here,
forking the Bishop and the Pawn.
The idea in my head when I played this
move was: I saw that my Bishop had now,
having served its role as
the guardian of the e4 square,
now it needed to find something else
to do: because with this pawn protected,
the - I don't need to worry
about supporting e4 anymore
and now it's just a wall in front of
my Bishop. So I thought, all right,
"let's move the Bishop out around the
wall and maybe go after these pawns,"
but what I missed was, oh my God,
I have just abandoned
the guard on this square,
and this beautifully placed
Knight should just leap there,
and win my h-pawn - er, my a-pawn.
Instead he plays this move,
which is weak. I get out of the fork -
although it would
probably have been better
to go out of the fork -
to just retreat the Bishop
and guard the square.
But instead, I allow him
this really good move,
which would take a7 again,
because I can't retreat the Bishop
to protect the pawn, because then
he just takes the Bishop with his Knight.
Okay, he misses it too. He brings in
the Knight, and I'm, like, alright, let's -
this pawn here -
it's going to be super weak.
I'm gonna take this Bishop -
take this Knight
with the Bishop,
lure his pawn onto the e5
square, and then it's vulnerable.
That was the idea
in my head. Actually,
the reality that position in the
cold light of analysis is that it's
"dynamically balanced."
The Pawn is weak,
but it is also strong.
It is dynamic play.
So i'm innocently going to
go and round up the pawn,
But I - my idea is to go here
next move - what I missed is that,
White has this fork, and
then he's checking the King,
and he's going to
pick up the Bishop.
But Matt!, you say, the Bishop
is guarded by the Knight!
Yeah, but he can TAKE the Knight,
removing the guard of the
Bishop, and THEN do the fork,
so it's not so easy.
He misses that idea and
he pushes the b-pawn.
I accidentally get the right
idea which is to go back here,
and chase the Knight away,
and THEN bring in the King.
He reinforces the Knight,
which is not so good,
and I bring in the King,
and I'm going to win this pawn.
So he checks me,
which is a bad idea;
I DO win the Pawn,
I am now UP material;
and he comes in here. What's he thinking?
He's going to go after this pawn here.
He is undercutting.
So I'm thinking here,
and I'm thinking to myself - you know,
I've got these passed pawns I want to push;
I want to get my king
to one of these squares;
and I want to protect this pawn.
So what's the best move for me? -
and I come up with this move,
which, the idea is, to protect the
pawn first, and then also kind of
guard this square, cause I'm worried
about - okay, what if he pushes here
and if he pushes
here then I can go here,
and the Knight protects
that square too -
and then he does indeed push g3,
and... and I see at this
point that this Bishop -
er, that this Knight has
no squares. It can't go here,
because the Knight guards it;
it can't go here because of the
King; it can't go here because
of the King, and it can't go here...
or can it?
Well, in fact, it CAN go there.
If the Knight goes here, then it LOOKS like
I can capture the Knight, but that is fake,
because then White has
this beautiful move Bf4+.
The King has to
move out of the way,
and then the Knight recovers -
the Bishop recovers the Knight,
and we just have an opposite-Bishop
endgame. Probably a draw.
Yeah, I've got the passed
Pawn; yeah I'm a Pawn up;
but White can just blockade
on the dark squares,
and, uh, and Black
has nothing. Okay.
So White has that resource,
which I did not see at the time,
so I moved the Bishop here.
I am very happy with myself.
All I have to do is take the Knight,
and there's nothing he can do to stop it.
So he did have
the Nc7 move, as -
he probably still loses,
but - it's his best option,
that - he kind of misses up the order
a little, what he does, is, he plays Bf4.
And now I have a choice to make:
do I abandon my Pawn?
I can either: move forward
here, then his Knight escapes;
or I can exchange the
Knight for the Bishop,
win this Pawn in exchange for this
one, and then I have TWO passed pawns,
supported by the King.
That's what I'm
going to do. Okay.
Take the Bishop. He takes back.
I take the Pawn. I'm in
check, I cannot save this Pawn:
the Bishop - the Knight's
going to take it. He takes it.
Now how do you get these passed pawns all
the way down to the board to make a Queen?
They're on light squares, and the
Bishop's on light squares too, so
Black has to be careful not to
allow White to set up a blockade,
and then the Knight is
going to come back,
and it's going to help out the King,
and it could be a tough struggle.
So, what I say to myself is,
I'm going to cut off the Knight -
I'm still sort of
entertaining ideas of,
maybe he'll make a mistake?
Like, he really only has one move in this
position. He has to move the Knight here.
Eh, that's not quite true.
But, um, the Knight has four
squares that it can move to,
and the Bishop covers
three of those squares,
so if the King can get in,
then he can win the Knight,
and then I'll be up a whole piece.
So that forces him to bring his
Knight to the edge of the board,
and I'm thinking all right, good
now I can move by King forward;
I can start advancing the pawns;
if the pawn goes here
it'll cover this square;
this is good.
So I moved the Knight -
I moved the King here,
because I want to prevent
the enemy King from
getting to the second rank,
and I like that I'm on this, like,
two-square diagonal move away from -
from the Knight, which means the Knight
will have to work very hard to check me,
and he moves his King there.
It might arguably in this position
have been better to move the King here,
because then it's not
in the way of the f-pawn.
The f-pawn is a more likely candidate
for promotion than the e-pawn is,
because the f1-square is a
light color, just like the Bishop,
whereas the e1
square is a dark color.
So it's easier for White to
blockade the dark square.
Of course, for the
f1-pawn to promote,
it has to get past the
f2-square, which is also dark,
so these are the
squares that are very key;
and this square, of course,
but that one I've gotten.
So anyway, I move the King
here, and he moves the King here,
and I push the Pawn -
okay, good, I'm blocking this -
He has this move,
forking the - the Bishop -
he has this move, forking
the Bishop and the Pawn,
but, like, I am totally willing
to give away the
h-pawn in this position,
if it means that his Knight is going
to go all the way to h7 for it.
Like, yeah! Great!
Do that! Please!
Uh, he's - he moves to Ke1.
He's got blockade ideas,
and so now I have to
think of how I'm going to
advance this f-pawn. Like,
I would love to go here,
but that drops the f-pawn with check, and
the Pawn can't advance if it's not there.
So I reject that idea.
Instead, I go here,
and now I've got this move, and then I've
got this move coming, and it'll be check,
and let's say he goes
here, then this will be mate,
or if he goes the other way,
then,
I can Queen!
So I'm liking this, I'm
liking this. He moves here.
He's attacking my Bishop.
More than just
attacking the Bishop:
he is threatening
to go here, check,
and that will attack my king
and it will attack my pawn.
And how do I protect my pawn
while not getting my King
taken? I have to go here,
and then I'm blocking
the Pawn again,
and now he has improved
his Knight's position.
He's also threatening to
take the Pawn, but, again,
you can have that Pawn,
dude. Take the Pawn.
Get your Knight, like, opposite
side of the board. I'll Queen. Great.
And here I had to think
a lot, because - it's not -
It's getting kind of crowded
over here if the Knight comes in,
and maybe the Knight goes here; maybe
the Knight sacrifices itself for the Pawn;
it's not clear to me that I
have a route to promote.
And White's got some tricks with
that Knight and his crazy jumps.
And so I thought, and I thought, and
I thought, and I came up with a very
beautiful move. One
of my favorite moves.
It was a blitz game: we had
five minutes on the clock to start,
three minute increment after each move, but
I thought for thirty seconds on this move.
So I'm gonna let YOU think, and see if
you come up with the same move that I did.
Okay? Here's what I did.
Why is this such a good move?
And why did I have to think so long?
Okay, from a strategic point of view,
the Knight has two
ways to get back
and help his King
block the pawns.
I mean there's also this, but that's stick-
ing the Knight on the edge of the board,
and the only way it can come in from there
there is this square, and that's covered,
so I'm not worried
about that so much;
and this move just covers
both of those squares;
and then I'm going to
advance the pawns,
and advance the pawns, and
advance the pawns, and Queen.
Also, this keeps eye on all of these pawns!
If any of these pawns advance, then that
weakens the ones in front of it.
I had to stop and think, because
what if he goes here check?
Well that's easy, Matt!
You moved the Bishop
there so you could
take him if he goes there!
Yes but what happens if I take him?
Well, he takes back.
That's exactly what
he did. He checked me;
and I took;
and he takes back.
And now what?
I had to calculate,
all the way back here,
I had to calculate
what would happen
if I moved the Bishop, and he checked
me, and then I took, and he took back:
and I saw that he had a
Pawn here, and he could go
one - two - three -
and get a Queen;
but I went for the move anyway,
because I saw that what my King could do,
and my pawns against his King,
was even better than a Queen,
and I'll show you what that was.
He checks; I take;
he takes back.
So the f-pawn is the key.
We push the f-pawn forward.
Well what's he gonna
do? He's gonna Queen.
This is - this guy here - this
White Pawn - this is like the White -
the wide receiver in football,
who has just blasted past the safety,
and he's waiting for the ball to come
and he reaches up his hands,
and the ball falls into his hands,
and he's running, and then he's going to
the end zone, and there's nobody between
him and the end zone, and
he's going to get a touchdown.
What's going on here?
This guy - this is like -
the quarterback is
on the one yard line;
and he gets the
ball from the center;
and the center pushes; and the
guard next to the center pushes;
and there's this defensive
tackle - defensive end;
and they're trying to stop the quarterback
from going over the one yard line and they
just push, and they
shove, and they get over.
And who wins? Who's
gonna make it to the end zone?
And who wins the
game? Let's see!
So I pushed, with check.
Interestingly, White has two moves
here. I only considered one.
I only considered this one which is the
move that was played in the game,
but the computer finds this move too
Like, maybe I instinctively
ignored it because I saw I could Queen;
and then once you get the
Queen the Queen is with check;
and then you can just go all the
way back down here and blockade;
and then you can Queen another
Queen; and you can round up
this pawn; and you can round up all
these other pawns; and then you can get
five Queens, total; and I should be
able to checkmate them with five Queens.
But it is all irrelevant, because
he actually moved to f1.
But what are you gonna
do about this Pawn, Matt?
Your King can't race back!
I move here.
Very simple.
Now at this point you're probably
thinking I begin to believe.
Okay, so he comes
forward; and I go forward;
and he Queens! He gets a Queen! Oh
no! It's a Pawn endgame! He has a Queen!
And I checkmate. That's mate.
White King is in check. White King
can't go here because of the Pawn.
White King can't go
here because of the Pawn.
Black King covers
these three squares.
Beautiful checkmate pattern.
And that is the story
how, in a Pawn endgame,
I allowed my opponent
to Queen; I did not Queen;
and I won! Thanks for watching.