(exhales) Nice.
Bishop endgame.
I love endgames, chat: I may
have mentioned that before.
Um... just push?
1, 2, 3, 4, 5 pawns for Black; 1, 2, 3,
4, 5 pawns for White. I love this little
formation here.
Like normally this is very weak,
but the fact that they're all
on light squares, and
our Bishop is on dark
squares means that, like,
It's actually,
paradoxically, quite strong.
And it's tempting to
suggest - oops. OH NO!
I meant to demonstrate
why that was the
wrong move, and I accidentally
made that move! Nooo!
Okay.
What is the real move here, chat?
The real move here is ... h2. Yes.
I was going to
come around to that.
Aargh... fail.
I failed, chat. I'm sorry.
I failed you all.
I'm a bad streamer.
I let my chat down.
Okay.
Anyway I was going to
demonstrate - let's analyze.
Okay.
Where is the analyze
button? There it is.
Okay. Anyway
chat, as I was saying,
Like it's tempting to
push this pawn, and then
a key sacrifice to allow this
pawn to push. But then this
pawn behind it covers.
So it's a strong
defensive formation.
But anyway, the idea of the
puzzle is to push the pawn...
where were we...
here. Okay. So,
we push the pawn.
If White takes, then you
just get the Bishop for free;
and, um... if White
moves his King here, then
you just take the Bishop anyway;
and the King cannot take
because then you promote.
So this is actually a
trap to win the Bishop,
by overloading the King.
Oh. man.
Aargh, it's depressing.
Aargh, mouseslip.
(exhales)
Okay! We start over.