Okay. PowerShell is no use to me here.
Let's start out with this opening
that I made up...
where we just move out all the Knights...
and all four center pawns.
And what should we do next?
Let's bring out the Bishops.
I don't like that.
It's too helpful.
Okay. Let's do 1. e4 e5;
2. d4 d5;
3. Nf3 Nf6;
bring out the Bishops;
and we castle.
Okay!
So we have Green, we have Yellow,
and we have Gray.
So we know there's no e4,
we know there's no Nf6,
and there's no Bc4,
and there's no Bc5,
and we know there's no O-O.
We're kind of done with PowerShell for this.
Let me add Chessle here.
Eh... I still need to adjust this scene.
Let's move that down a little...
... there we are.
Let's add more text here.
Okay!
For Yellow we have an e5...
... and a d4...
Rearrange the order in a minute.
e5, d4, d5,
Nf3.
We have no Greens.
One, two, three, four...
we have four Yellows.
One, two, three, four, five...
we have five Grays.
We count O-O as Gray because
it's the same...
(okay, cool...)
like, we can't tell whether
it's Black or White that castles...
so this gray O-O means that
neither side castles during the opening.
Okay, d4 is very probably White's move.
So, Guess.
So, I think pretty...
I'm going to guess that it's 1. d4
and then 1. ... d5.
Although e5?
Having e5 and d4 in the same opening is
a little weird. Maybe it's a French?
No because there's no e4.
So how can there be an e5?
It must be...
Black that plays ... e5,
because otherwise White would have
had to play e4 first. Okay.
So 1. d4
1. ... d5
and then 2. c4 maybe.
Let me just draw them out here.
So I think it's going to be like this.
I'm not going to make this my submission.
And then I think
it's e5 HERE.
Maybe not right away.
Like the ... e5 must happen before
White plays the Knight.
So maybe right away?
And then, takes...
and then here...
and then ... c5...
here. I've covered e5,
d4 and d5, and Nf3.
Okay. So my guess is that it's...
1. d4 d5
2. c4 c5...
no. 1. d4 d5 2. c4 e5
3. dxe5
No this can't be it,
because there's a d4.
So how do you play this opening...
without d5-d4...
given that it's White to move?
Okay, material's even.
There's no Nf6.
4. ... c5?
Let's go here.
There's no d4.
5. ... d4 seems like such
a natural move here.
There might be a ... d4!
BOTH sides could play d4.
Okay, so what are the
unique moves in my guess?
d4 and d5...
we already knew about.
c4 and e5 we already,
well, e5 we already knew about,
Nf3 we already knew about, so the unique
elements of this guess are c4.
So I w... - so I want to try c4,
I want to try exd4,
I want to try Nxd4
I want to try c4...
I want to try c5,
I want to try Nb5,
and I kind of wanna
try d4 twice.
Some of these are more
natural than others.
So I'm going to go all the way
back to the beginning,
and I'm going to guess 1. c4.
Okay.
Now, I can't really try exd4 or Nxd4
because they rely on d4
which I don't want to bother with,
but there is 1. ... c5.
Now, let's try 2. Nc3.
We haven't tried that.
And I'm going to try 2. ... e6.
Keep the Knight out.
And I want to try 3. g3.
I know it's NOT 3. ... d5,
so I'm going to try 3. ... g6,
and fianchetto both Bishops.
I don't want to bother with Nf3.
I know there's a d4 so I
don't want to bother with d5 -
I mean, I know there's a d4 so
I don't want to bother with d3.
Hey therock_dwayne,
thanks for the follow!
Welcome to Chessle.
I could try 5. b3.
What do I know about e-pushes?
We know e5 is a move.
Oh, well if I know e5 is a move
then I don't want to bother with e6.
Okay. So I'll do 2. ... g6
right away and 3. g3
and we'll fianchetto,
and then let's do the b-pawns,
and we'll fianchetto this way too.
Okay.
So we got another yellow!
This is good.
Let me rearrange these
alphabetically.
d4 d5
e5
Nf3.
We know c4 is a yellow,
and we know g3 is a yellow.
Oh, it's looking like a Catalan.
Okay.
Uh, let's try our other grays.
We know there's no c5.
Let me put these in
alphabetical order too.
Knight comes here.
c5, there's no c5.
We know there's no Nc3.
We know there's no g6.
How far can you see?
You can see up to O-O. Okay.
All right, so let's cut this off here
and do a new line. Okay.
Actually, let's cut it off here.
Okay, c5, Nc3, g6,
Bg7,
Bg2,
b6,
b3,
(I don't have any greens!)
and Bb7. Okay.
Okay, so we do know, one
two three four five six,
we know six yellow moves.
We know c4,
e5, d4, d5, Nf3, g3.
It's probably in this order:
1. d4 d5
2. c4...
it's Black's move...
Black does, something,
I dunno, let's do...
uh, we know it's NOT 2. ... Nf6...
we know... let's try 2. ... c6.
Caro-Kann.
Well, not a Caro-Kann. A Slav.
Caro-Kann is with the e-pawn
instead of the c-pawn.
And then let's do 3. g3,
and let's do 3. ... takes.
We know he doesn't play
the Knight - 4. Bg2,
and we know he doesn't do 4. e4.
What does he do?
4. Qc2 maybe? 4. Qc2 is a terrible idea,
because you take the...
Pbbt.
All right, let's back it up.
Okay, we think it's 1. d4 d5.
And we know there's a c4,
so it might as well be here.
We think the next move is
going to be 3. g3.
No, the next move isn't 3. g3.
g3 comes later.
Or it could be on move 2.
Let's do 2. ... take, 3. Nf3.
We know there's a d5.
Maybe it's here.
Oh, it's White's - Black's move.
There's no e4. It could be a ... c-takes.
So, Black is up a pawn here.
Okay, so what moves do I want to try?
d4, d5, c4; those are on the yellow list.
I want to try dxc4. That seems
like a reasonable try.
Nf3 is on my yellow list.
I want to try e5. e5's on my yellow list.
Good, I got that in there.
g3. g3 is on the yellow list.
I want to try exd4, Qxd4, Qxd4.
Okay. So let's go back and
let's try those moves
WITHOUT duplicating the moves
that we already know are yellow.
Okay.
Well I have to get
a Pawn to c4.
There's only one yellow Knight move!
Let's do it this way.
I want to get the Knight there.
Have I tried Nc6?
I have not.
And I want to try this.
One, two three; one, two three. Okay.
Three attackers, three defenders.
Let's try that.
Okay, good! We got green.
Got some greens.
We got 1. d4 d5 2. c4.
And, we know that they
don't take: that's gray.
Okay.
And we know there's no Nc3 -
oh, I DID know there was no Nc3!
Why did I play Nc3?
That was a waste.
Idiot!
Okay, I know e5 is not THERE.
It's probably on the 2nd move, then.
There's no e3.
e3 comes before e4.
Let me make this a little smaller.
There we go.
Uh, we now know where Nc6 is.
Okay.
We're narrowing it
down very well here,
but we have to get everything right
in order to win.
So this is tricky.
Okay.
So, we - let's try 2. ... e5 right away.
This is a move.
It's not a very good move,
but you do see it.
And...
it's actually quite common
for White to take here.
We know that the
Knight comes to c6,
So that makes it unlikely
that he takes on d5.
There could be a second d4.
Uh, we haven't tried this move,
have we? Nd7? No. I mean, Ne7?
NOW 4. g3.
4. ... Nc6.
And we know there's no Bg2.
Maybe take here?
And then Queen takes?
Okay, so this fits with all our greens.
d4, d5, c4 -
Nbc6! Okay, it does NOT. Okay.
Nbc6 is not the same as Nc6.
Okay, so 3. ... d4.
We know there's a g3.
Let's do HERE.
NOW the 4. ... Nc6.
Let's do 5. f4,
and let's do 5. ... Bc5.
Okay.
"1. d4 d5 2. c4 ?"? Yes.
2. ... e5 - that's a yellow.
I'll get to the yellows.
"?", another d4.
Okay. 4 g3 Nc6.
Okay, so it matches all of our greens.
Let's check all the yellows.
Is there a c4? Yes, on move 2.
This does not...
This is not conflict with
1. c4 on move 1. Cool.
d4. 1. d4 is on move 1. Yes.
This is not yellow anymore.
This is green.
d5. Yes. Also not yellow anymore.
In fact, c4 isn't yellow
anymore either.
Is there an e5? Yes we have
the 2. ... e5 as Black's move two.
Is there a g3? Yes.
Is there a Nf3?
No, I did not ever move Nf3!
Okay, so let's back it up.
Instead of 5. f4
let's do 5. Nf3,
and then 5. ... Bb- Bc5.
Okay. Overprotecting.
We could also do 5. ... Bg4.
I think maybe I will.
The idea is to threaten to take
the Knight and then to take the Pawn,
and then White can pin.
Let's try that.
Oh, so close!
Okay, we got the first few moves!
We got 1. d4 d5 2. c4 e5!
e5 is no longer yellow.
We have 3. dxe5!
And then we have a second d4!
They did a double letter!
Good-good-good-good-good.
Okay. So the g3 is in
the puzzle somewhere.
It's not move 1, it's not move 2, it's not
move 3, it's not move 4. It MUST be move 5.
So I'm guessing this is 5. g3.
So now all we need to do is
figure out what White's move is here.
Okay, so what are our grays?
We got another gray.
We got another Bg4 here.
Let me just check that we have
all the grays. We have e4,
we have Nf6,
yes; we have Bc4, Bc5; O-O;
we have c5;
we have Nc3; g6;
Bg7, of course, we can't
do Bg7 if there's no g6;
Bg2, of course;
b6; b3; Bb7;
no fianchettoing at all;
the dxc4 is gray; Nc3,
we knew that twice (stupid!);
e3; Nge2; okay;
Bb4, also gray;
okay; okay-okay-okay;
and Bg4! Good. So that's all of our grays.
Okay, so we know it's
all right up to this point.
Now what moves does White have that we
haven't tried yet? We haven't tried Bb4.
I can't highlight on this board.
But, like this is the idea.
So, we know 4. g3 and 5. Nf3 are the right
moves - they're just in the wrong order!
Okay so it's  4. Nf3 right away,
and then 4. ... Nc6,
and then 5. g3, and now we know
every move except for Black's last.
We know it's not 5. ... Bg4, even
though that seems like a sensible move.
Could it be 5. ... Bb4+?
We know that it's not Bb4, but this
would be WITH A CHECK and that changes
the symbol, which means it's not quite
the same move from a Chessle sense.
Okay, let's try that.
Oh, so close!
Okay, so we know everything
except the last move!
What is Black's move here?
It's not 5. ... Bc5, we tried that
already. We have a gray.
It's not 5. ... Bb4+.
Could be 5. ... Be7?
We know it's not 5. ... Nge7 - or -
Nge2 or Nge7?
It could be 5. ... Nge7.
It could very well be this.
We have not tried that.
Okay, the idea being to go to g6.
Okay, let's try that.
Oh yeah!
38% of people got it right today.
Six tries.
I need to be careful about
not reusing greens.
Like, I reused a lot of greens in this
puzzle and that really slowed me down.
But it took me:
one, two, three, four, five, six.
Chessle: six!