So what is Semantle?
Semantle is a game
where you try to guess the secret word,
and it has nothing to do with how it is spelled,
it has everything to
do with what it means.
For example
If the word
is "GRAPE"
Then "ORANGE" will be very
similar because they're both fruit.
Let me adjust this...
Okay! So I'm gonna guess
something generic... I'm gonna guess...
"HUMAN" is very very cold.
Let me rearrange things a little.
Okay! So "HUMAN" is
extremely UN-similar.
Let's try "CAR."
Still cold. Okay.
Let's try "KITCHEN."
Still very cold. Okay.
Let's try "LOVE."
Let's try...
"NATION."
Let's try "LAUNDRY."
"CAT."
"ELEPHANT."
"PLANET."
"POLITICS."
Closer.
"POLITICS" but not "NATION."
Uh, "GEOGRAPHY."
"DEMOCRACY."
Okay, "POLITICS" but not "DEMOCRACY."
How about "EMOTION?"
No, "LOVE" would be very close.
How about "ARGUE?"
"COMPETITION."
Ooo! Okay, so "POLITICS"
has a competitive element.
How about a sport?
How about "TENNIS?"
How about "BATTLE?"
Competition...
"GAME."
Okay, "GAME" is the closest I've got so far.
How about "CHESS?"
"CARDS?"
"POKER?"
Tepid! Woo!
Gettin' there...
We can try other card games...
How about "TAROT?"
What other competitive games are
there that don't use cards?
"FOOTBALL."
Why are the numbers out of order?
Oh, I see. These are
the ones that are closest.
How about "BLACKJACK?"
Okay, "POKER..." "BLACKJACK..."
What other games do you
play with cards? "BRIDGE?"
Hmm...
A blackjack is a weapon.
You can hit somebody over the
head with it, like a club.
How about "CASINO?"
"BLACKJACK" is closer.
"GAMBLE?"
"LUCK?"
"CARDSHARK?"
"I don't know the word
'CARDSHARK.'" Okay.
"DEALER?"
Okay, "BLACKJACK" is quite close.
"SLOT?"
Wow!
Okay it's... "BLACKJACK" is close to "SLOT"
because you play slot machines in a casino.
(exhales)