So, hold on.
So, todays xkcd has this CAPTCHA where
you have to figure out where the mines are,
and so I thought I would try to
take a hand at solving it.
So this is a take-off on the game
Minesweeper, where you're given all these
numbers, and then blank squares,
and you have to try to figure out
what numbers belong
in the blank squares.
The number tells you how many
mines are in adjacent squares.
So of the three squares that
are adjacent to the corner -
and diagonal counts -
two of them have mines;
and of the four squares that are
adjacent to this one over here,
only one of them has a mine;
and so we should be able to do,
with some logic, figure out
which the question marks
are mines, and which are not.
So I will use M for Mine;
and I will use C = Clear;
? = Unknown.
Okay, so let's start
with this 3 here:
three of these are mines,
but of these two squares -
B3 and A4 - they
can't BOTH be mines,
because if they were
both mines, then this
square would have at least
two mines adjacent to it.
So only one of these is a
mine, and the other one is clear:
that is to say, between these two squares -
there's only one mine between them,
which means that both
of these have to be mines.
M, M.
Okay.
I still don't know which one of these
is the mine, and which one is clear,
but now that I look at this 2, I can see
that there's already two mines next to it
so this one must be clear,
and in fact, if I look
at this 1 here,
of these four, I know that three of
them are clear and the other one's a mine.
So this is clear, this is
clear, and this is clear.
Okay.
In fact I know that
not only is this clear,
but this is a 2.
When you normally play Minesweeper,
and you click on a box (that's NOT a mine)
it'll give you the number;
but we're not playing that
kind of Minesweeper; we're doing
"xkcd CAPTCHA" Minesweeper.
Okay.
So this guy here has three
mines next to it, which means that
two of these are mines,
and the third one is clear;
and, by a very similar exercise,
these two are both next
to this number 1 here,
which means only one of these can
be clear, and the other one's a mine;
so to get this all the
way up to three, we need
one of these, AND this
one. So this one is a mine.
I don't know which one of these it
is, but now that I had put this M here,
this 3 is full; so I
know this guy is clear,
and this 1 is clear, so I know
that all of these three are clear.
I could also use the same logic
between this 3 and this 1,
to prove that only one of these is a
mine, and therefore THIS is a mine,
but I don't need it. So I can
use a C here, and a C here,
and a C here (because of this 1.)
Okay, and now there's
only one square left,
and we know it's a
mine because of this,
and we know it's the
third mine for this guy.
Okay, and so the answers are -
ah! -
"Shapes;" okay -
answers are: here,
here, here, and here.
And let's just do a last check:
the 2 has two mines next to it;
the 1 has one mine next to it;
the 3 has three mines next to it;
the 1 has one;
and the 1 has one:
so, this checks out!
Thank you for watching me
solve xkcd's Minesweeper puzzle.